<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
- phpMyAdmin XML Dump
- version 4.5.2
- https://www.phpmyadmin.net
-
- Host: localhost
- Generation Time: Jan 07, 2016 at 04:38 PM
- Server version: 5.6.27
- PHP Version: 5.6.16
-->

<pma_xml_export version="1.0" xmlns:pma="http://www.phpmyadmin.net/some_doc_url/">
    <!--
    - Structure schemas
    -->
    <pma:structure_schemas>
        <pma:database name="ADnD2nd" collation="latin1_swedish_ci" charset="latin1">
            <pma:table name="Wizard_Spell">
                CREATE TABLE `Wizard_Spell` (
                  `id` int(11) NOT NULL AUTO_INCREMENT,
                  `name` varchar(50) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `school` varchar(50) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `level` int(1) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `ranged` varchar(50) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `components` varchar(10) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `duration` varchar(50) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `casting_time` varchar(25) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `area_of_effect` varchar(25) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `saving_throw` varchar(15) DEFAULT NULL,
                  `description` text,
                  `Reversible` tinyint(1) NOT NULL,
                  PRIMARY KEY (`id`)
                ) ENGINE=InnoDB AUTO_INCREMENT=46 DEFAULT CHARSET=latin1;
            </pma:table>
        </pma:database>
    </pma:structure_schemas>

    <!--
    - Database: 'ADnD2nd'
    -->
    <database name="ADnD2nd">
        <!-- Table Wizard_Spell -->
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">1</column>
            <column name="name">Affect Normal Fires</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">5 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">2 Rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">10-foot radius</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">This spell enables the wizard to cause nonmagical fires-from as small as a torch or lantern to as large as the area of effect-to reduce in size and brightness to become mere coals or increase in light to become as bright as full daylight and increase the illumination to double the normal radius. Note that this does not affect either fuel consumption or damage caused by the fire. The caster can affect any or all fires in the spell's area. He can alter their intensities with a single gesture as long as the spell is in effect. The spell lasts until the caster cancels it, all fuel is burned, or the duration expires. The caster can also extinguish all flames in the area, which expends the spell  immediately. The spell does not affect fire elementals or similar creatures.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">2</column>
            <column name="name">Alarm</column>
            <column name="school">Abjuration, Evocation</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">10 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">4 hours + 1/2 hour/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1 round</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Up to a 20-foot cube</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When an &lt;i&gt;alarm&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast, the wizard causes a selected area to react to the presence of any creature larger than a normal rat-anything larger than about one-half cubic foot in volume or more than about three pounds in weight. The area of effect can be a portal, a section of floor, stairs, etc. As soon as any creature enters the warded area, touches it, or otherwise contacts it without speaking a password established by the caster, the &lt;i&gt;alarm&lt;/i&gt; spell lets out a loud ringing that can be heard clearly within a 60-foot radius. (Reduce the radius by 10 feet for each interposing door and by 20 feet for each substantial interposing wall.) The sound lasts for one round and then ceases. Ethereal or astrally projected creatures do not trigger an alarm, but flying or levitating creatures, invisible creatures, or incorporeal or gaseous creatures do. The caster can dismiss the alarm with a single word.
            The material components of this spell are a tiny bell and a piece of very fine silver wire.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">3</column>
            <column name="name">Armor</column>
            <column name="school">Conjuration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">Touch</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">Special</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1 round</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 creature</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">By means of this spell, the wizards creates a magical field of force that servers as if it were scale mail armor (AC 6). The spell has no effect on a person already armored or a creature with Armor Class 6 or better. It is not cumulative with the &lt;i&gt;shield&lt;/i&gt; spell, but it is cumulative with Dexterity and, in the case of fighter/mages, with the shield bonus. The &lt;i&gt;armor&lt;/i&gt; spell does not hinder movement, adds no weight or encumbrance, nor does it prevent spellcasting. It lasts until successfully dispelled or until the wearer sustains cumulative damage totaling greater than 8 point +1 per level of the caster. (It is important to note that the armor does  absorb this damage. The armor merely grants an AC of 6; the wearer still suffers full damage from any successfull attacks.) Thus, the wearer might suffer 8 points from an attack, then several minutes later sustain an additional 1 point of damage. Unless the spell were cast by a wizard of 2nd level or higher, it would be dispelled at this time. Until it is dispelled, the &lt;i&gt;armor&lt;/i&gt; spell grants the wearer full benefits of the Armor Class gained.
            The material component is a piece of finely cured leather that has been blessed by a priest.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">4</column>
            <column name="name">Audible Glamer</column>
            <column name="school">Illusion/Phantasm</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">60 yards + 10 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">3 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Hearing range</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">When the &lt;i&gt;audible glamer&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast, wizard causes a volume of sound to arise, at whatever distance he desires (within range), and seem to recede, approach, or remain at a fixed place as desired. The volume of sound created, however, is directly related to the level of the spellcaster. The volume is based upon the lowest level at which the spell can be cast, 1st level. The noise of the &lt;i&gt;audible glamer&lt;/i&gt; at this level is that of four men, maximum. Each additional experience level of the wizard adds a like volume, so that at 2nd level the wizard can have the spell cause sound equal to that of eight men. Thus, talking, singing, shouting, walking, marching, or running sounds can be created. The auditory illusion created by an &lt;i&gt;audible glamer&lt;/i&gt; spell can be virtually any type of sound, but the relative volume must be commensurate with the level of the wizard casting the spell. A horde of rats running and squeaking is about the same volume as eight men running and shouting. A roaring lion is equal to the noise volume of 16 men, while a roaring dragon is equal to the noise volume of no fewer than 24 men.
            A character stating that he does not believe the sound receives a saving throw, and if it succeeds, the character then hears a faint and obviously false sound, emanating from the caster's direction. Note that this spell can enhance the effectiveness of the &lt;i&gt;phantasmal force&lt;/i&gt; spell.
            The material component of the spell is a bit of wool or a small lump of wax.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">5</column>
            <column name="name">Burning Hands</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">Instantaneous</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">The caster</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">1/2</column>
            <column name="description">When the wizard casts this spell, a jet of searing flame shoots from his fingertips. His hands must be held so as to send forth a fan-like sheet of flames: the wizard's thumbs must touch each other abd the fingers must be spread. The burning hands send out flame jets of five-foot length in a horizontal arc of about 120 degrees in front of the wizard. Any creature in the area of the flames suffer 1d3 hit points of damage, plus 2 points for each level of experience of the spell-caster, to a maximum of 1s3 + 20 points of fire damage. Those successfully saving vs. spell receive half damage. Flammable materials touched by the fire burn (e.g., cloth, paper, parchment, thin wood, etc.). Such materials can be extinguished in the next round if no other action is taken.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">6</column>
            <column name="name">Cantrip</column>
            <column name="school">All Schools</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">10 feet</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">1 hour/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Special</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">Cantrips are minor spells studied by wizards during their apprenticeship, regardless of school. The &lt;i&gt;cantrip&lt;/i&gt; spell is a practice method for the apprentice, teaching him how to tap minute amounts of magical energy. Once cast, the &lt;i&gt;cantrip&lt;/i&gt; spell enables the caster to create minor magical effects for the duration of the spell. So minor are these effects that they have severe limitations. They are completely unable to cause a loss of hit points, cannot affect the concentration of spellcasters, and can only create small, obviously magical materials. Furthermore, materials created by a cantrip are extremely fragile and cannot be used as tools of any sort. Lastly, a cantrip lacks the power to duplicate any other spell effects.
            Whatever manifestation the cantrip takes, it remains in effect only as long as the wizard concentrates. Wizards typically us cantrips to impress common folk, amuse children, and brighten dreary lives. Common tricks with cantrips include tinklings of ethereal music, brightening faded flowers, glowing balls that float over the caster’s hand, puffs of wind to flicker candles, spicing up aromas and flavors of bland food, and little whirlwinds to sweep dust under rugs. Combined with the  spell, these are the tools to make housekeeping and entertaining simpler for the wizard.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">7</column>
            <column name="name">Change Self</column>
            <column name="school">Illusion/Phantasm</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">2d6 rounds + 2 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">The caster</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">This spell enables the wizard to alter the apearance of his form-including clothing and equipment-to appear one foot shorter or taller; thin, fat, or in between; human, humanoid, or any other generally manshaped bipedal creature. The caster cannot duplicate a specific individual. The spell does not provide the abilities or mannerisms of the chosen form. The duration of the spell is 2d6 rounds plus two additional rounds per level of experience of the spellcaster. The DM may allow a saving throw for disbelief under certain circumstances: for example, if the caster acts in a manner obviously inconsistent with his chosen role. The spell does not alter the perceived tactile (i.e., touch) properties of the caster or his equipment, and the ruse can be discoverd in this way.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">8</column>
            <column name="name">Charm Person</column>
            <column name="school">Enchantment/Charm</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">120 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">Special</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 person</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Neg.</column>
            <column name="description">This spell affects any single person it is cast upon. The term &lt;i&gt;person&lt;/i&gt; includes any bipedal human, demi-human, or humanoid of man-size or smaller, such as brownies, dryads, dwarves, elves, gnolls, gnomes, goblins, half-elves, halflings, half-orcs, hobgoblins, humans, kobolds, lizard men, nixies, orcs, pixies, sprites, troglodytes, and others. Thus, a 10th-level fighter could be charmed, but an ogre could not.
The person receives a saving throw vs. spell to avoid the effect, with any adjustment due to Wisdom (see Table 5). If the person receives damage from the caster group in the same round the &lt;i&gt;charm&lt;/i&gt; is case an additional bonus of +1 per hit point c damage received is added to the victim saving throw.
If the spell recipient fails his saving throw, he regards the caster as a trusted friend and ally to be heeded and protected. The spell does not enable the caster to control the charmed creature as if it were a automaton, but any word or action of the caster is viewed in the most favorable way. Thus, a charmed person would not obey suicide command, but he might believe the caster if assured that the only chance to save the caster‘s life is for the person to hold back an onrushing red dragon for “just a round o two.” Note also that the spell does no endow the caster with linguistic capabilities beyond those he normally possesses (i.e., he must speak the victim’s language to communicate his commands).
The duration of the spell is a function of the charmed person’s Intelligence and is tied to the saving throw. The spell may be  broken if a successful saving throw is rolled, and this saving throw is checked on a periodic basis, according to the creature’s Intelligence (see the following table). If the caster harms, or attempts to harm, the charmed person by some overt action, or if a dispel magic spell is successfully cast upon the charmed person, the &lt;i&gt;charm&lt;/i&gt; spell is broken.
If two or more &lt;i&gt;charm&lt;/i&gt; effects simultaneously affect a creature, the result is decided by the DM. This could range from one effect being clearly dominant, to the subject being tom by conflicting desires, to new saving throws that could negate both spells.
Note that the subject has full memory of the events that took place while he was harmed.

&lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th align=center&gt;Intelligence Score&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;th align=center&gt;Time Between Checks&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td align=center&gt;3 or less&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td align=center&gt;3 months&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;4 to 6&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;2 months&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;7 to 9&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;1 month&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;10 to 12&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;3 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;13 to 14&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;2 weeks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;15 to 16&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;1 week&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;3 days&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;2 days&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;19 or more&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td align=center&gt;1 day&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

The period between checks is the [me period during which the check occurs. When to roll the check during this time is determined (randomly or by selection) by the DM. The roll is made secretly.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">9</column>
            <column name="name">Chill Touch</column>
            <column name="school">Necromancy</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">3 rounds + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">The caster</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Neg.</column>
            <column name="description">When the caster completes this spell, a blue glow encompasses his hand. This energy attacks the life force of any living creature upon which the wizard makes a successful melee attack. The touched mature must roll a successful saving throw vs. spell or suffer ld4 points of damage and lose 1 point of Strength. If the save is successful, the creature remains unharmed. Creatures not rated for Strength suffer a -1 penalty to their attack rolls for every other successful touch. Lost Strength returns at the rate of 1 point per hour. Damage must be cured magically or healed naturally.
            This spell has a special effect on undead creatures. Undead touched by the caster suffer no damage or Strength loss, but they must successfully save vs. spell or flee for 1d4 rounds + 1 round per level of the caster.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">10</column>
            <column name="name">Color Spray</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">Instantaneous</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">5’ x 20’ x 20’ wedge</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">Upon casting this spell, the wizard causes a vivid, fan-shaped spray of clashing colors o spring forth from his hand. From one to six creatures (1d6) within the area are affected in order of increasing distance from the wizard. All creatures above the level of the pellcaster and all those of 6th level or 6 Hit Dice or more are entitled to a saving throw ‘s. spell. Blind or unseeing creatures are not affected by the spell.
	          Creatures not allowed or failing saving hrows, and whose Hit Dice or levels are less han or equal to the spellcaster’s level, are struck unconscious for 2d4 rounds; those with Hit Dice or levels 1 or 2 greater than be wizard’s level are blinded for ld4 mnds; those with Hit Dice or levels 3 or more greater than that of the spellcaster are stunned (reeling and unable to think or act coherently) for one round. The material components of this spell are a pinch each of powder or sand that is colored red, yellow, and blue.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">11</column>
            <column name="name">Comprehend Languages</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">Touch</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">5 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1 round</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 speaking creature or written object</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When this spell is cast, the wizard is able to understand the spoken words of a creature or read an otherwise incomprehensible written message (such as writing in another language). In either case, the wizard must touch the creature or the writing. Note that the ability to read does not necessarily impart understanding of the material, nor does the spell enable the caster to speak or write an unknown language. Written material can be read at the rate of one page or equivalent per round. Magical writing cannot be read, other than to know it is magical, but the spell is often useful when deciphering treasure maps. This spell can be foiled by certain warding magics (the 3rd-level &lt;i&gt;secret page&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;illusionary script&lt;/i&gt; spells) and does not reveal messages concealed in otherwise normal text.
            The material components of this spell are a pinch of soot and a few grains of salt.
            The reverse of this spell, &lt;i&gt;confuse languages&lt;/i&gt; cancels a &lt;i&gt;comprehend languages&lt;/i&gt; spell or renders a writing or creature's speach incomprehensible, for the same duration as above.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">12</column>
            <column name="name">Dancing Lights</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">40 yards + 10 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">2 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Special</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When a &lt;i&gt;dancing lights&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast, the wizards creates, at his option, from one to four lights that resemble either torches or lanterns (and cast that amount of light), glowing spheres of light (such as evidenced by will-o-wisps), or one faintly glowing, vaguely man-like shape, somewhat similar to that of a creature from the elemental plane of fire. The dancing lights move as the spellcaster desires, forward or back, straight or turning corners, without concentration upon such movement by the wizard. The spell cannot be used to cause blindness (see 1st-level &lt;i&gt;light&lt;/i&gt; spell), and it winks out if the range or duration is exceeded.
            The material component of this spell is either a bit of phosphorus or wychwood, or a glowworm.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">13</column>
            <column name="name">Detect Magic</column>
            <column name="school">Divination</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">2 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">10' path, 60' long</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When the &lt;i&gt;detect magic&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast, the wizard detects magical radiations in a path 10 feet wide and up to 60 feet long, in the direction he is facing. The intensity of the magic can be determined (dim, faint, moderate, strong, overwhelming), and the wizard has a 10% chance per level to recognize if a certain type of magic (alteration, conjuration, etc.) is present. The caster can turn, scanning a 60-degree arc per round. Astone wall of one foot or more in thichness, solid metal of one inch thickness, or a yard or more of solid wood blocks the spell. Magical areas, multiple types of magic, strong local magical emanations may confuse or conceal weaker radiations. Note that this spell does not reveal the presence of good or evil, or reveal alignment. Other-planar creatures are not necessarily magical.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">14</column>
            <column name="name">Detect Undead</column>
            <column name="school">Divination/Necromancy</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">3 turns</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1 round</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">60' + 10'/level</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">This spell enables the caster to detect all undead creatures out to the range of the spell. The area of effect extends in a path 10 feet wide and 60 feet long (plus 10 feet longer per level of the wizard), in the direction the caster is facing. Scanning a direction requires one round, and the caster must be motionless. While the spell indicates direction, it does not give specific location or distance. It detects undead through walls and obstacles but is blocked by one foot of solid stone, one yard of wood or loose earth, or a thin coating of metal. The spell does not indicate the type of undead detected, only that undead are present.
            The material component for this spell is a bit earth frtom a grave.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">15</column>
            <column name="name">Enlarge</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">5 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">5 rounds/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 creature or object</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Neg.</column>
            <column name="description">This spell causes instant growth of a creature or object, increasing both size and weight. It can be cast only upon a single creature (or a symbiotic or community entity) or upon a single object that does not exceed ten cubic feet in volume per caster level. The object or creature must be seen to be affected. It grows by up to 10% per level of experience of the wizard, increasing this ammount in height, width, and weight.
            All equipment worn or caried by a creature is enlarged by the spell. Unwilling victims are entitled to a saving throw vs. spell. A successful saving throw means the spell fails. If insufficient room is available for the desired growth, the creature or object attains the maximum possible size, bursting weak enclosures in the process, but it is constrained without harm by stronger materials-the spell cannot be used to crush a creature by growth.
            Magical properties are not increased by this spell-a huge &lt;i&gt;sword +1&lt;/i&gt; is still only +1, a staff-sized wand is still only capable of its normal functions, a giant-sized potion merely requires a greater fluid intake to make its magical effects operate, etc. Weight, mass, and strength are affected, though. Thus a table blocking a door would be heavier and more effective, a hurled stone would have more mass (and cause more damage), chains would be more massive, doors thicker, a thin line turned into a sizeable, longer rope, and so on. A creature's hit points, Armor Class, and attack rolls do not change, but damage rolls increase proportionately with size. For example, a fighter at 160% normal size hits with his long sword and rolls a 6 for damage. The adjusted damage roll is 10 (that is, 6 x 1.6 = 9.6, rounded up). Bonuses due to Strength, class, and magic are not altered.
            The reverse spell, &lt;i&gt;reduce&lt;/i&gt;, negates the &lt;i&gt;enlarge&lt;/i&gt; spell or makes creatures or objects smaller. The creature or object loses 10% of its original size for every level of the caster, to a minimum of 10% of the original size. Thereafter, the size shrinks by one-foot increments to less than one foot, by one-inch increments to one inch, and by 1/10-inch increments to a minimum of 1/10 of an inch-the recipient cannot dwindle away to nothingness. For example, a 16-foot-tall giant reduced by a 15th-level wizard (15 steps) would be reduced to 1.6 feet (in nine steps), then to 6/10 of a foot or 7.2 inches (in one step), and finally to 2.2 inches (in the last five steps). A shrinking object may damage weaker materials affixed to it, but an object will shrink only as long as the object itself is not damaged. Unwilling creatures are allowed a saving throw vs. spell.
            The material component of this spell is a pinch of powdered iron.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">16</column>
            <column name="name">Erase</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">30 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">Permanent</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 scroll or 2 pages</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">The &lt;i&gt;erase&lt;/i&gt; spell removes writings of either magical or mundane nature from a scroll or from one to two pages of paper, parchment, or similar surfaces. It removes &lt;i&gt;explosive runes, glyphs of warding, sepia snake sigils,&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;wizard marks&lt;/i&gt;, but it does not remove &lt;i&gt;illudionary script&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;symbols&lt;/i&gt; (see these spells). Nonmagical writings are automatically erased if the caster is touching them, otherwise the chance of success is 90%. Magical writings must be touched, and are only 30% likely to be erased, plus 5% per caster level, to a maximum of 90% (e.g., 35% for a 1st-level caster, 40% for a 2nd-level caster, etc.).
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">17</column>
            <column name="name">Feather Fall</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">10 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V</column>
            <column name="duration">1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Special</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When this spell is cast, the creature(s) or object(s) affected immediately assumes the mass of a piece of down. Rate of alling is instantly changed to a mere two feet per second (120 feet per round), and no damage is incurred upon landing while the spell is in effect. However, when the spell duration ceases, normal rate of fall occurs. The spell can be cast upon the wizard or some other creature or object up to the maximum range and lasts for one round for each level of the wizard. The &lt;i&gt;feather fall&lt;/i&gt; affects one or more objects or creatures in a 10-foot cube, as long as the maximum weight of the creatures or object does not exceed a combined total of 200 pounds plus 200 pounds per level of the spellcaster.
              For example, a 2nd-level wizard has a range of 20 yards, a duration of two rounds, and a weight limit of 600 pounds when casting this spell. The spell works only upon free-falling, flying, or propelled objects (such as missiles). It does not affect a sword blow or a charging creature. Note that the spell can be effectively combined with a &lt;i&gt;gust of wind&lt;/i&gt; and similar spells.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">18</column>
            <column name="name">Find Familiar</column>
            <column name="school">Conjuration/Summoning</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">1 mile/level</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">Special</column>
            <column name="casting_time">2d12 hours</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 familiar</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">This spell enables the caster to attempt to summon a familiar to act as his aide and companion. Familiars are typically small creatures, such as cats, frogs, ferrets, crows, hawks, snakes, owls, ravens, toads, weasels, or even mice. A creature acting as a familiar can benefit a wizard, conveying its sensory powers to its master, conversing with him, and serving as a guard/scout/spy as well. A wizard can have only one familiar at a time, however, and he has no control over what sort of creature answers the summoning, if any at all come.
            The creature is always more intelligent than others of its type (typically 2 or 3 Int points), and its bond with the wizard confers upon it an exceptionally long life. The wizard receives the heightened senses of his familiar, which grants the wizard a +1 bonus to all surprise die rolls. Normal familiars have 2-4 hit points plus 1 hit point per caster level, and an Armor Class of 7 (due to size, speed, etc.).
            The wizard has an empathic link with the familiar and can issue it mental commands at a distance of up to one mile. Note that empathic responses from the familiar are generally fairly basic-while able to communicate simple thoughts, these are often overwhelmed by instinctual responses. Thus a ferret familiar spying on a band of orcs in the woods might lose its train of thought upon sighting a mouse. Certainly its communications to its master would be tinged with fear of the “big ones” it was spying on! The caster cannot see through the familiar’s eyes.
            If separated from the caster, the familiar loses 1 hit point each day, and dies if reduced to 0 hit points. When the familiar is in physical contact with its wizard, it gains the wizards saving throws against special attacks. If a special attack would normally cause damage, the familiar suffers no damage if the saving throw is successful and half damage if the saving throw is failed. If the familiar dies, the wizard must successfully roll an immediate system shock check or die. Even if he survives this check, the wizard loses 1 point from his Constitution when the familiar dies.
            The power of the conjuration is such that it can be attempted but once per year. When the wizard decides to find a familiar, he must load a brass brazier with charcoal. When this is burning well, he adds 1,000 gp worth of incense and herbs. The spell incanation is then begun and must be continued until the familiar comes or the casting time is finished. The DM secretly determines all results. Note that most familiars are not inherently magical, nor does a dispel magic spell send them away.
            Deliberate mistreatment, failure to feed and care for the familiar, or continuous unreasonable demands have adverse effects on the familiar’s relationship with its master. Purposely arranging the death of one‘s own familiar incurs great disfavor from certain powerful entities, with dire results.
            &lt;table&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;D20 Roll&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Familiar *&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Sensory Powers&lt;/th&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1-5&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Cat, black&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Excellent night vision &amp; superior hearing&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;6-7&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Crow&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Excelent vision&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;8-9&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Hawk&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Very superior distance vision&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;10-11&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Owl&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Night vision equals human daylight vision, superior hearing&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;12-13&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Toad&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Wide-angle vision&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;14-15&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Weasel&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Superior hearing &amp; very superior olfactory power&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;16-20&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;No familiar&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;available in spell range&lt;/td&gt;
              &lt;/tr&gt;
              * The referee can substitute other small animals suitable to the area.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">19</column>
            <column name="name">Friends</column>
            <column name="school">Enchantment/Charm</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">1d4 rounds + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">60-foot radius</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">A friends spell causes the wizard to temporarily gain 2d4 points of Charisma. Intelligent creatures within the area of effect at the time the spell is cast must make immediate reaction checks based on the character’s new Charisma. Those with favorable reactions tend to be very impressed with the spellcaster and make an effort to be his friends and help him, as appropriate to the situation. Officious bureaucrats might decide to become helpful; surly gate guards might wax informative; attacking orcs might spare the caster’s life, taking him captive instead. When the spell wears off, the creatures realize that they have been influenced, and their reactions are determined by he DM.
			The components for this spell are chalk (or white flour), lampblack (or soot), and vermilion applied to the face before casting the spell
			</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">20</column>
            <column name="name">Gaze Reflection</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">2 rounds + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Special</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">The &lt;i&gt;gaze reflection&lt;/i&gt; spell creates a shimmering, mirror-like area of air before the wizard that moves with the caster. Any gaze attack, such as that of a basilisk, &lt;i&gt;eyes of charming&lt;/i&gt;, a vampire's gaze, the 6th-level &lt;i&gt;eyebite&lt;/i&gt; spell, and so on, is reflected back upon the gazer if the gazer tries to make eye contact with the spellcaster (the spellcaster suffers no effects from the gaze attack). Such creatures receive a saving throw vs. their own gaze effect. The spell does not affect vision or lighting and is not effective against creatures whose effect comes from being gazed upon (such as a medusa). Only active gaze attacks are blocked by this spell.
			</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">21</column>
            <column name="name">Grease</column>
            <column name="school">Conjuration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">10 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">3 rounds + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">10' x 10' square area</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">A &lt;i&gt;grease&lt;/i&gt; spell covers a material surface with a slippery layer of a fatty, greasy nature. Any creature entering the area or caught in it when the spell is cast must save vs. spell or slip, skid, and fall. Those who successfully save can reach the nearest non-&lt;i&gt;grease&lt;/i&gt; surface by the end of the round. Those who remain in the area are allowed a saving throw each round until they escape the area. The DM should adjust saving throws by circumstance; for example, a creature charging down an incline that is suddenly &lt;i&gt;greased&lt;/i&gt; has little chance to avoid the effect, but its ability to exit the affected area is almost assured! The spell can also be used to create a greasy coating on an item-a rope, ladder rungs, weapon handle, etc. Material objects not in use are always affected by this spell, while creatures wielding or employing items receive a saving throw vs. spell to avoid the effect. If the initial saveing throw is failed, the creature immediately drops the item. A saving must be made each round the creature attemps to use the &lt;i&gt;greased&lt;/i&gt; item. The caster can end the effect with a single utterance; otherwise it lasts for three rounds plus one round per level.
            The material component of the spell is a bit of pork rind or butter.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">22</column>
            <column name="name">Hold Portal</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">20 yards/level</column>
            <column name="components">V</column>
            <column name="duration">1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">20 square feet/level</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">This spell magically bars a door, gate, or valve of wood, metal, or stone. The magical closure holds the portal fast, just as if it were securly closed and locked. Any extraplanar creature (djinn, elemental, etc.) with 4 or more Hit Dice can shatter the spell and burst open the portal. A wizard of 4 or more experiance levels higher than the spellcaster can open the held portal at will. a &lt;i&gt;knock&lt;/i&gt; spell or a successful &lt;i&gt;dispell magic&lt;/i&gt; spell can negate the &lt;i&gt;hold portal&lt;/i&gt;. Held portals can be broken or physically battered down.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">23</column>
            <column name="name">Hypnotism</column>
            <column name="school">Enchantment/Charm</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">5 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, S</column>
            <column name="duration">1 round + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">30-foot cube</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Neg.</column>
            <column name="description">The gestures of the wizard, along with his droning incantation, cause 1d6 creatures within the area to become suspectible to a suggestion-a brief and reasonable-sounding request (see the 3rd-level wizard &lt;i&gt;suggestion&lt;/i&gt; spell). The request must be given after the &lt;i&gt;hypnotism&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast. Until that time the success of the spell is unknown. Note that the subsequent suggestion is not a spell, but simply a vocalized urging (the caster must speak a language the creature understands for this spell to work). Creatures that successfully roll their saving throws are not under hypnotic influence. Those who are exceptionally wary or hostile save with +1 to +3 bonusses. If the spell is cast at an individual creature that meets the caster's gaze, the saving throw is made with a penalty of -2. A creature that fails its saving throw does not remember that the caster enspelled it.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">24</column>
            <column name="name">Identify</column>
            <column name="school">Divination</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">0</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">Special</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">1 item/level</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">When an &lt;i&gt;identify&lt;/i&gt; spell is cast, magical items subsequently touched by the wizard can be identified. The eight hours immediately preceding the casting of the spell must be spent purifying the items and removing influences that would corrupt and blur their magical auras. If this period is interrupted, it must be begun again. When the spell is cast, each itme must be handled in turn by the wizard. Any consequences of this handling fall fully upon the wizard and may end the spell, although the wizard is allowed any applicable saving throw.
            The chance of learning a piece of information about an item is equal to 10% per level of the caster, to a maximum of 90%, rolled by the DM. Any roll of 96-00 indicates a false reading (91-95 reveals nothing). Only one function of a multi-function item is discovered per handling (i.e., a 5th-level wizard could attempt to determine the nature of five different items, five different functions of a single item, or a combination of the two). If any attempt at reading fails, the caster cannot learn any more about that item until he advances a level. Note that some items such as special magical tomes, cannot be identified with this spell.
            The item never reveals its exact attack or damage bonuses, although the fact that it has a few or many bonuses can be determined. If it has charges, only a general indication of the number of charges remaining is learned: powerful (81-100% of the total possible charges), strong (61-80%), moderate (41-60%), weak (6-40%), or faint (five charges or less). The faint result takes precedence, so a fully charged &lt;i&gt;ring of three wishes&lt;/i&gt; always appears to be only faintly charged.
            After casting the spell and determining what can be learned from it, the wizard loses 8 points of Constitution. He must rest for one hour to recover each point of Constitution. If the 8-point loss drops the spellcaster below a Constitution of 1, he falls unconscious. Consciousness is not regained until full Constitution is restored, which takes 24 hours (one point per three hours for an unconscious character).
            The material components of this spell are a pearl (of at least 100 gp value) and an owl feather steeped with wine, with the infusion drunk prior to spellcasting. If a &lt;i&gt;luckstone&lt;/i&gt; is powdered and added to the infusion, the divination becomes much more potent: exact bonuses or charges can be determined, and the functions of a multi-functional item can be learned from a single reading. At the DM's option, certain properties of an artifact or relic might also be learned.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">25</column>
            <column name="name">Jump</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">Touch</column>
            <column name="components">V, S, M</column>
            <column name="duration">1d3 rounds + 1 round/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">Creature touched</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">None</column>
            <column name="description">The individual touched when this spell is cast is empowered to leap once per round for the duration of the spell. Leaps can be up to 30 feet forward or straight upward or 10 feet backward. Horizontal leaps forward or backward have only a slight arc-about two feet per 10 feet of distance traveled. The jump spell does not ensure safety in landing or grasping at the end of the leap.
            The material component of this spell is a grasshopper’s hind leg, to be broken by the caster when the spell is cast.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">26</column>
            <column name="name">Light</column>
            <column name="school">Alteration</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">60 yards</column>
            <column name="components">V, M</column>
            <column name="duration">1 turn/level</column>
            <column name="casting_time">1</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">20-foot-radius globe</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">Special</column>
            <column name="description">This spell creates a luminous glow, equal to torchlight, within a fixed radius of the spell’s center. Objects in darkness beyond this sphere can be seen, at best, as vague and shadowy shapes. The spell is centered on a point selected by the caster, and he must have a line of sight and unobstructed path for the spell when it is cast. &lt;i&gt;Light&lt;/i&gt; can spring from air, rock, metal, wood, or almost any similar substance.
            The effect is immobile unless it is specifically centered on a moveable object or mobile creature. If this spell is cast upon a creature, the applicable magic resistance and saving throw rolls must be made. Successful resistance negates the spell, while a successful saving throw indicates that the spell is centered immediately behind the creature, rather than upon the creature itself. &lt;i&gt;Light&lt;/i&gt; taken into an area of magical darkness does not function, but if cast directly against magical darkness negates it (but only for the duration of the &lt;i&gt;light&lt;/i&gt; spell, if the darkness effect is continual).
            &lt;i&gt;Light&lt;/i&gt; centered on the visual organs of a creature blinds it, reducing its attack rolls and saving throws by 4 and worsening its Armor Class by 4. The caster can end the spell at any time by uttering a single word.
            The material component is a firefly or a piece of phosphorescent moss.
            </column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">27</column>
            <column name="name">Magic Missile</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">28</column>
            <column name="name">Mending</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">29</column>
            <column name="name">Message</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">30</column>
            <column name="name">Mount</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">31</column>
            <column name="name">Nystul's Magical Aura</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">32</column>
            <column name="name">Phantasmal Force</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">33</column>
            <column name="name">Protection From Evil</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">34</column>
            <column name="name">Read Magic</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">35</column>
            <column name="name">Shield</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">36</column>
            <column name="name">Shocking Grasp</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">37</column>
            <column name="name">Sleep</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">38</column>
            <column name="name">Spider Climb</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">39</column>
            <column name="name">Spook</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">40</column>
            <column name="name">Taunt</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">41</column>
            <column name="name">Tenser's Floating Disc</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">42</column>
            <column name="name">Unseen Servant</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">43</column>
            <column name="name">Ventriloquism</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">44</column>
            <column name="name">Wall of Fog</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="Wizard_Spell">
            <column name="id">45</column>
            <column name="name">Wizard Mark</column>
            <column name="school">NULL</column>
            <column name="level">1</column>
            <column name="ranged">NULL</column>
            <column name="components">NULL</column>
            <column name="duration">NULL</column>
            <column name="casting_time">NULL</column>
            <column name="area_of_effect">NULL</column>
            <column name="saving_throw">NULL</column>
            <column name="description">NULL</column>
            <column name="Reversible">0</column>
        </table>
    </database>
</pma_xml_export>
